UTKARSH GAUR

+1 416-371-9661 utkarshgaur@outlook.com 3040 Knob Hill, Mississauga, Ontario

Computer Engineer with 5+ years of field experience. I have spent the past three years shifting my focus from networking hardware to software development. I'm now seeking an opportunity to bring my game dev and web dev experience to an agile-oriented team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science and Engineering (BASc)

May 2013

Engineering Science, Major in Electrical and Computer Engineering University of Toronto, St. George Campus

SKILLS

Programming LanguagesC#, Java, C++, HMTL, CSS, JavaScript **Applications**Unity, MonoDevelop, Microsoft Visual Studio **Second Languages**French (conversational), Hindi (fluent)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Game Developer

Mar 2015 – Present

Self-Employed, Mississauga, Ontario

- Developed multiple games using C# and Unity Editor
- Rigorously followed Test-Driven Development (TDD) via Unity Test Tools
- Coded enemy AI and card game mechanics
- Developed project management strategies for self-driven goals

Applications Engineer

Nov 2013 – Dec 2014

Calnex Solutions, Linlithgow, Scotland and Ottawa, Ontario

- Designed lab test environments around the Attero product line
- Managed technical support and technical sales for the Attero
- Troubleshot customer issues
- Directed features development

Applications Architect

May 2010 – Jun 2011

Bell Canada, Toronto, Ontario

- Automated Quality Assurance (QA) using Tcl and AutoIT
- Performed QA on and debugged Routing Gateways (RG) for the internet, working with multiple teams
- Proposed and developed a bug tracking solution with real-time backups

PERSONAL SKILLS AND HOBBIES

Public Speaking
President
Hobbies
Advanced Communicator Silver Award (Oct 2013) from Toastmasters
"University of Toronto Engineering Toastmasters" club (2010-2011)
Writing short stories, biking along trails, playing video-games

References Available Upon Request